# Celine Guise

Newark, DE ● celineguise1@gmail.com ● 302-893-8412 linkedin.com/in/celineguise ● github.com/celineguise ● Website

Enthusiastic and initiative-taking professional looking to make an impact through working with data. Known for excellent leadership, interpersonal, and communication skills and the ability to collaborate effectively in diverse environments. Has spent the last four years in an economics PhD program — bringing strong economic research, econometrics, and quantitative background.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Advanced in Stata, Microsoft Excel, Python (Pandas and Seaborn), Jupyter Notebooks, and SQL.
- Strong in economic modeling and intuition, reduced-form econometrics, and statistical modeling.
- Strong communication and collaboration skills, with the ability to lead and motivate individuals.
- Working knowledge in C++ and Java.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Doctor of Philosophy** in Economics

ABD

University of Delaware - Newark, DE

GPA: 3.48

Master of Science in Economics and Applied Econometrics

May 2021

University of Delaware – Newark, DE

GPA: 3.48

**Bachelor of Science** in Computer Science

May 2019

University of Delaware - Newark, DE

Concentration: Economics, Minor: Economics

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **PHD Research** – University of Delaware

August 2021 – Present

- Investigates how the Affordable Care Act impacts a younger individual's likelihood to work in the gig economy, using the deployment of Uber as a proxy.
- Analyzes and processes 1.5 million data points across ten years of US Census employment data.
- Merges 240 Uber deployment regions to the dataset using state and county FIPS codes.
- Shows 22 to 25 year old individuals are 0.04% less likely to work for companies like Uber or Lyft compared to 27 to 29 year old individuals post mandate of the Affordable Care Act.

### **Head Teaching Assistant** – University of Delaware

August 2020 – Present

- Leads review sessions for introductory economic courses to 120 students to reinforce course material.
- Creates instructional material for three teaching assistants to use to strengthen student study skills.
- Mentors three teaching assistants on how to teach course material and improve test scores.
- Manages the course gradebook for all 275 students to keep students informed on their weekly progress.

### **Professor** – University of Delaware

June 2022 – July 2022, Jan 2023 – Feb 2023

- Taught accelerated courses to 15 students on Macroeconomics, and Economic Issues and Policies.
- Tutored students during office hours and helped students improve their test scores by 10 to 15 percent.
- Received positive feedback from 90 percent of students for approachability and teaching style.

### **Assistant IT Technician** – Applied Control Engineering

June 2018 – August 2020

- Managed a ticket system to help 100 users with their computer and network problems.
- Updated and managed network software, firmware, mailboxes, and company servers.